Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
DUMMY LINE: ready for Anaya
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your meal has arrived.
Why is it spoiled again? You...
You are lucky to have food to eat.
Take it if you want.
Or I will feed the dog with it.
No!
No! Please don't!
It's better than having nothing to eat.
The tableware will be collected in 3 hours.
Let's go.
Even these [dog] servants can now bully us.
They must have skimmed our
food allotment to flatter their masters.
Keep your voice down.
They wouldn't be so bold without permissions.
Vermilion.
Heat these two dishes.
Also,
our palace is about to run out of charcoal.
The Household Department hasn't
sent any in a long time.
It seems like the weather will change soon.
My Lady is hungry.
Let's heat the food for her before anything else.
Yes.
Let's go.
My Lady, these few dishes are still fresh,
I just asked Vermilion to heat it for you.
Please eat it while it is warm.
I am not hungry.
Please divide it among yourselves.
My Lady,
if you refuse to eat and your health collapses,
all the servants in the Palace of Pearl Jade
will have no one to rely on.
Leave me half of a steamed bun.
The rest will be shared among you all.
Yes.
My Lady.
You are growing thinner and thinner every day.
Is it because you feel unwell?
I suppose I am mentally exhausted.
I am always feeling fatigued.
And my waist is sore.
This is not good.
We have to bring imperial doctors here somehow.
Forget it.
They won't agree to come.
When Xiao-Yunzi got a fever two days ago,
they didn't even allow him to get medicine.
It's lucky that he is strong enough to get through it.
Otherwise, he might not have survived it.
My Lady, you have a weak constitution.
Xiao-Yunzi could recover, but you might not.
I have to figure out a way.
I must bring an imperial doctor for you.
Jade, look after My Lady.
Don't worry, Madam.
I will do my best.
All right, Vermilion come with me.
Sir! Sir!
- Open the door!
- Please Open the door!
- Concubine Sourire is ill!
- Please open the door!
Xiao-Yunzi kneels before you!
Sir!
Her Highness is very ill!
His Majesty only placed Her Highness in confinement
but didn't say that she couldn't see a doctor.
If anything happens to Her Highness ...
You ... We would all be held accountable.
Here, I have some silver,
You could buy everyone some drinks.
I'm begging of you, sir!
His Majesty ordered that
no one can come out of this palace.
Nothing else is our concern.
Close the door!
Please don't!
Please! don't close the door, sir!
Sir, please open the door! Sir!
My Lady,
I am incompetent ...
I couldn't send for a doctor.
It's fine.
Don't cause trouble to the guards.
I can still pull through.
Vermilion.
Help me up to take a walk.
My Lady, what are you going to do?
Maybe I can feel better with the help of Earth Qi.
My Lady!
Are you all right? My Lady!
Sir! Open the door!
Open the door! Open the door!
Open the door!
Concubine Sourire has fainted!
Open the door! Her Highness fainted!
Xiao-Yunzi, kick the door open!
What are you doing?
Don't stop me!
Let me out! Let go of me!
Back!
Stay back! How dare you!
Her Highness fainted.
Take your hands off me! Let me out!
I dare you to come closer!
Let me out!
Let me go!
Let go!
Vermillion!
- Vermillion!
Vermillion ...
- Call the ...
- Vermillion.
- Imperial doctors.
Go. Go to report to the Chief!
Yes.
- Vermillion.
- Call the imperial doctors.
Imperial doctors! Bring the doctors!
Your Majesty.
The Chief of Guards has an emergency to report.
Your Majesty, I must report this emergency.
Go on.
Your Majesty, servants in the Palace of
Pearl Jade attempted to pass the guards.
The guards held their positions.
But one maid was injured in the conflict.
They are very bold even to have dared
to challenge the guards.
Do you know why they did so?
Your Majesty, the guards reported that
it was because Her Highness fainted,
and the servants wanted to bring a doctor.
The guards blocked their way
as per ordered by Your Majesty ...
How dare you!
I have only ordered confinement.
But you dared to prevent
Concubine Sourire from seeing a doctor!
If anything happens to her,
can you bear the consequences?
My guilt deserves a thousand deaths.
The leader of the guards will seek his
punishment from the Department of Penalty.
Yes.
- Su Peisheng.
- Your Majesty.
Immediately, send doctors for Concubine Sourire.
Yes.
In case anything happens, report it to me at once.
It has to be Dr. Wen.
Yes.
My Lady is awake.
Don't move. There is chilblain medicine on your hands.
It will take time to recover.
You must be hungry.
Bring it here.
Dr. Wen specially ordered the bird's nest
to be made with ejiao.
My Lady, you should have some while it's warm.
Dr. Wen.
Your Highness.
I congratulate Your Highness.
Congratulations, Your Highness!
Your Highness,
Dr. Wen said that you have been pregnant for one month.
- Jinxi.
- Aye.
You and Dr. Wen will stay.
Others may leave.
Your Highness, I have just taken your pulse.
Your emotions have been changing
radically that your prenatal qi is unstable.
You must avoid such harm to your health.
Dr. Wen,
what is your assessment of my situation now?
Now is the only chance for Your Highness
to turn the situation around.
His Majesty has been informed of your pregnancy
and ordered that I will take care of Your Highness.
The Empress also commands extra care
for Your Highness's food and supplies.
Your Highness can rest assured of your situation.
Can I?
Do you think
that this is my chance to turn the situation around?
If so,
in all the orders you have mentioned,
why haven't I heard of the order to rescind my confinement?
Nor has His Majesty sent any words of comfort.
The so-called care for me—
it's only for my child,
not for me.
Your Highness.
Don't worry.
In any case,
I will not belittle my own life
or let my child suffer.
I am reassured.
Noble Lady Vertu and I were worried
that Your Highness might compromise your health.
As Your Highness says so,
I will do my best to take care of Your Highness.
You have known me for a long time.
Have you seen me ever depreciating myself?
I entrust
the safety of me and the baby in my belly
to you, Dr. Wen.
I assure Your Highness
that I will take the best care of Your Highness
and your baby with all my abilities.
This is not for Your Highness,
but also for the care and concern that Lady Vertu has for Your Highness.
Meizhuang must be very worried
all these days while I have been confined.
It's true.
She could neither sleep nor eat well.
Their Majesties both refused her
outside their palace gates.
She had her heart burning in anxiety.
Tell Meizhuang not to worry about me.
I am all right.
I will.
Your Highness should devote a
peaceful mind to the baby.
I shall take my leave.
Jinxi.
Being pregnant is good news.
I believe His Majesty will stop being so hardhearted.
It's fortunate that Your Highness
will be attended by Dr. Wen.
I trust him.
Do you also feel that His Majesty
is too hardhearted?
Many children in the palace
died before they were born.
Each step ahead of us will not be easy.
Your Highness has to be very cautious.
Jinxi,
bring me the ink brush.
Your Highness is still weak.
If you need to write something,
please wait until you are better.
Please bring it.
Yes.
Now that I'm pregnant,
His Majesty will not refuse to read my letter.
Try to send this to His Majesty.
What has Your Highness written?
I plead with His Majesty
to put the Empress in charge of my prenatal care.
The Empress?
Doesn't Your Highness suspect that
she was behind what happened to you?
Why do you ask for her supervision?
No one in the harem now can balance with her power.
I can't solely depend on myself to protect my child.
Since she has plotted against me,
she must resent me deeply
and will also detest my child.
Now, I want her to take charge of my prenatal care.
If anything went amiss,
she would be the first one to blame.
Therefore, she must exert all her means
to ensure my child is safely born.
This seems the best way to ensure safety for now.
If Your Highness wants to regain favor,
it will all depend on this child.
I only hope my child can grow up safe and sound.
Take this.
I'm afraid the bird's nest has already turned cold.
I will mix it with some warm milk.
You can do it later.
I've been craving something with stronger flavours.
Ask Vermillion to prepare some
shrimp congee in the kitchen.
Have you been able to calm your mind
after these days?
I haven't been unable to.
I keep hearing news from the Palace of Pearl Jade,
but I cannot even go near for a visit.
You can tell the Emperor is indeed furious.
So I caution you
not to stand up at the "teeth of the storm".
It is at the "teeth of the storm" that
Concubine Sourire is having her hardest time.
At this juncture, Concubine Sourire
should be having a hard time.
This is only normal.
If the Emperor could still treat her as usual,
then I should be concerned.
But Concubine Sourire was
only wearing a wrong robe.
Why would His Majesty be like this?
Although I never asked,
I believe there are other reasons.
I implore Your Majesty to save Concubine Sourire.
Now is not the right time.
I cannot agree to this.
Your Majesty...
You don't understand.
The Emperor needs to vent out all his anger.
When his anger is calmed,
Concubine Sourire can then have
a chance to regain favor.
Or else even when her confinement ends,
do you think her life will be any easier?
This incident concerns Empress Première.
If the Emperor does not change
his own mind, no one else can.
My Lady.
You are now pregnant.
The food you eat will nourish for two.
Please try to eat more.
Where is Vermillion?
I didn't see her when you all were here.
My Lady, are you unsatisfied with my service?
You keep asking about Vermillion.
Where is Vermillion?
Don't worry.
Vermillion has not ...
rested well these two days.
She caught a cold and is sleeping now.
I will go check on her.
My Lady.
Vermillion has just gone to sleep,
and you have also just woken up.
Why not check on her later?
Don't stop me. I will go check ...
My Lady.
There is no need to go.
Vermillion ...
She is no longer with us.
What did you say ?
How do you think we managed to bring in Dr. Wen?
The guards outside ignored all our pleas.
Vermillion ...
confronted their swords ...
and the guards called in doctors
fearing that casualties would be involved.
It was fortunate that Dr. Wen was sent.
But Vermillion ...
had lost her life.
Jade! You...
I agreed not to tell My Lady ...
in case this affects her pregnancy.
Your Highness ...
I know you feel deep grief,
but no matter how much grief Your Highness feels,
you have to put your own well-being
above all else in the current circumstance.
Vermillion died for Your Highness...
Your Highness must not let her life be lost in vain!
Only when Your Highness is well and good
can you then avenge Vermillion's death.
Vermillion grew up with me ...
She is like my sister by blood.
- My Lady!
- Please don't, My Lady!
Your Highness, your hands were just wrapped.
You would hurt yourself beating them like this!
Did Your Highness forget the death of Lady Chun?
If you could endure then, why can't we
also endure the pain just for now?
Should Your Highness hurt yourself,
you would only be powerless
to avenge Vermillion in the future.
Right.
I must live on my life
so her death isn't in vain.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Peace and grace to Imperial Mother.
Rise.
Yes.
My peace is not of concern.
My concern is the peace of the imperial heir.
Do you mean Concubine Sourire's
pregnancy, Imperial Mother?
The Emperor told me
that Concubine Sourire wants you to be
in charge of her prenatal care.
I'm afraid I am incapable.
I failed to save my First Prince ...
You are capable.
That, I have faith in you.
Since it's your order, Imperial Mother,
I must not decline.
It is my duty to look after all the concubines.
It's good that you know your duties.
If you wish to secure your status,
you need to complement strength with gentleness.
You are an empress of the Great Qing
and also an empress from the Ula-Nara clan.
Each act and every move of yours
not only draws attention from all
but also relates to the honor of the entire clan.
You are my niece [cousin's daughter ].
I hope you can preserve the glory of an empress
and the glory of the Ula-Naras.
Yes.
Peace to others also means peace to yourself.
It's rare that you would come to see me.
I have been feeling weak since
my recovery from the plague.
I could not serve Your Majesty and
I hope Your Majesty will pardon me.
You didn't rush here just to say this.
Concubine Sourire is pregnant.
I beg Your Majesty to forgive her.
I didn't let you come in to say this to me.
Your Majesty agreed to see me, so you
knew I would certainly bring this up.
Go on and say what you want,
but it's my decision whether to listen.
I beg Your Majesty to pity the imperial heir.
How can Concubine Sourire's baby rest
well when she's in sorrow and privation?
I've already punished Chief Gou.
And read her letter
and approved that the Empress
will take care of her pregnancy.
I've also ordered her stipends
to be restored as Concubine.
But Concubine Sourire is deeply dispirited.
Without Your Majesty's forgiveness,
she won't be able to overcome her grief
Will Your Majesty allow me to
accompany her and raise her spirits.
I will give everything I could.
But I have already spoiled Concubine Sourire so much
that she has forgotten
"the bounds of Heaven and Earth".
She deserves some punishment.
Enough!
Your Majesty, Her Majesty the Empress
requests an audience.
Show her in.
Yes.
You should leave.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
- Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
- Rise
I saw Lady Vertu left.
She must have come to make the same request.
Your Majesty,
Concubine Sourire is pregnant.
Your Majesty should visit her.
It's all right.
It's not necessary for now.
I will see her eventually
when the child is born.
Concubine Sourire is still confined
in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
I wonder if your Majesty would lift her confinement.
No need.
Let her rest quietly there
in case she makes other mistakes.
Then I will send doctors to check her pulse regularly
and attend to her diet and health.
Make sure she is accompanied
if she wants to go to the Imperial Garden.
You take charge of these trivial matters from now.
No need to ask me.
Yes, Your Majesty.
My Lady, this bib from Lady Vertu is so nicely made.
It's sure to look cute on your baby.
You have been pregnant for five months.
His Majesty never visited.
His Majesty must be disgusted with me so utterly.
There's nothing we can do about His Majesty.
However, Consort Estime and Consort Honnête
always send comforting words through Dr. Wen.
Conversely, Concubine An has never asked about you.
It sends chills to the heart.
People's hearts change like temperature.
It’s always easy to share prosperity but
hard to bear adversity together.
People’s hearts have always been this way.
Why do I feel chilled?
Your Highness.
Dr. Wen.
Lady Vertu bid me bring you
a box of ejiao cakes.
"A free heart is unconfined."
Meizhuang is always thinking about me.
I have good news for Your Highness, too.
I believe Your Highness will
feel relieved after hearing it.
Please say it.
Your Highness is confined in the palace.
You have been afraid of implicating
your family outside.
You can rest assured about this.
As far as I know
your family is not implicated.
But they are very worried about
Your Highness's situation.
This news from you, Dr. Wen,
is indeed comforting to me.
Please tell my family that
I am all good.
There's no need to worry about me.
I understand what is proper to say.
Dr. Wen came just now.
He said that Concubine Sourire's
pregnancy is stable and everything is fine.
Her pregnancy is stable…
Your Majesty, it looks like Concubine Sourire
will "have her melon ripe and dropped"
in a few months.
Your Majesty, should we…
His Majesty asked me to take care of
Concubine Souire's pregnancy and childbirth.
How could I betray his trust?
At this juncture,
no one can make trouble in front of me.
What if she loses her child herself?
I heard that Concubine Sourire
has always been in low spirits.
But it’s no good to be so sad during pregnancy.
Otherwise, it would affect the baby.
Far more than that.
In the last months of pregnancy,
it could accidentally kill both
the mother and the child.
Qian Mingshi's Aromatic Ancient Pavilion
is a collection of rebellious poems.
I have dismissed him, seized his property, and exiled him to his hometown.
All officials in the capital must
write poems to denounce him.
These poems will be compiled and
published for nationwide distribution.
Have you finished doing that?
Your Majesty, I have read the poems carefully.
The very best poem is written by Fang Bao,
the chief compiler of the Yingwu Hall.
Counselor of the Princes, Chen Wance's
work is also quite creative.
But Chen Bangyan and Wu Xiaodeng wrote poems
that sympathize with Qian Mingshi.
When it comes to such matters,
it shows me if the officials are loyal.
Since I acceded to the throne, I have been worried
that the opposing faction hasn’t been eliminated.
This is a good time to investigate whether
there is anyone disloyal among the officials.
Since Chen Bangyan and Wu Xiaodeng
sympathize with Qian Mingshi,
Chen Bangyan will be dismissed
and Wu Xiaodeng will be banished to Ningguta.
Yes, Your Majesty.
But there is one thing I dare not
conceal from Your Majesty.
Say it.
Zhen Yuandao, Mr. Zhen, didn’t write
poems to condemn Qian Mingshi.
Mr. Zhen said he had poor literary talent
and his poems wouldn't be presentable.
So he demurred.
He has always been a civil official.
How can he not be good at verse?
Do you think so?
As I have reported to Your Majesty,
Zhen Yuandao secretly keeps the
rebellious book of Qian Mingshi.
This time, Zhen Yuandao refused to write
poems to condemn Qian Mingshi
to clarify his stance.
I am afraid of Zhen Yuandao harbors
treasonous intent in his mind.
Don't intimidate Zhen Yuandao in my name.
Instead, advise him tactfully.
Give him three days.
This will be forgiven if he’s willing
to condemn Qian Mingshi.
Otherwise,
I will also punish him.
Yes.
But Zhen Yuandao is the father of Concubine Sourire.
I'm afraid
that it would affect Her Highness's pregnancy.
That would not be desired.
I know what is proper.
Go and ask Qian Mingshi personally
why Zhen Yuandao had his poem anthology.
Yes.
Dr. Wen.
Please report my arrival.
Unfortunately, My Lady is asleep.
Her Highness is pregnant,
so she should have a good rest.
I'll just wait in the corridor.
By the way, Jade,
are My Lady’s cramps getting better?
They are still the same.
My Lady can't sleep well at night.
You should make her more bone soup
with a little vinegar added.
She should eat more tofu, vegetables, and fruits daily.
These can alleviate cramps.
She should also drink some milk before
going to bed, so she can sleep better.
Yes.
I will make bone soup every day for My Lady.
Jade, is that Dr. Wen outside?
Bring him in.
Yes, My Lady. Dr. Wen, please.
Please excuse my bluntness.
Your Highness can’t sleep well, mainly because
you are burdened with thoughts and concerns.
This can’t be relieved by medicine.
You already knew this.
Why bother to mention it again?
You need to report to Her Majesty later.
Please send my regards to Her Majesty.
And say I am well.
Yes.
As entrusted by His Majesty,
she doesn't dare to slight [snub?neglect?]
Your Highness or your unborn child.
She often summons me to ask about you.
You know how to answer her.
Certainly.
Jade.
Come with me to collect the herbs.
Take them back and brew them here as usual.
Remember to serve Her Highness by your own hand.
Don't let anyone else meddle.
Yes.
You are very thoughtful, Dr. Wen.
Is Meizhuang’s injured hand better?
It's been much better.
Although Lady Vertu recovered slowly,
after all, her wound completely healed before summer.
However, it just left a little scar.
A scar?
Didn't she use the Scar Relief Gel?
I have to go to the Palace of Great Benevolence.
I shall take my leave.
Your Highness...
If Lady An has anything sent to Your Highness,
make sure you won't use it
until I have checked.
Dr. Wen.
You have told me not to burden myself
with thoughts during my pregnancy.
But you are mincing your words.
Aren't you intentionally making me worry?
Please speak freely with me.
The Scar Relief Gel…
Something was added to the Scar Relief Gel.
Musk?
Is there musk in the Scar Relief Gel?
Yes. A large amount of musk was mixed into the Scar Relief Gel.
If you smear the gel on your wounds,
your will body absorb the musk just as you take it orally.
Additionally, the strong floral scent of the gel overshadows the smell of musk;
only a spice expert is able to produce it.
Your Highness. Other people besides Lady An could have mixed the musk into the gel.
After all, this gel is accessible to anyone in your palace.
-Your Highness.
- My Lady.
Your Highness.
Do you feel sick?
That woman [or person/people] makes me sick.
Has Meizhuang ...
known about this?
I dare not say anything.
You mustn't let her know about this.
If An Linrong really did this...
What a scheming mind she has.
I'm in such a plight now.
Meizhuang must be more isolated than ever.
Be sure to pass my words to her:
Don't ever displease the Empress and An Linrong.
Do you understand?
You can go now.
My Lady, you should be pleased.
Should I?
Yes.
My Lady has always doubted over Lady An's motives.
Though she hid in the dark before,
she is an open enemy now.
Isn't it easier to guard ourselves against her?
As we are in the light,
it's better to have fewer enemies in the dark.
My Lady, are you sad about your
sisterly bond with Lady An?
Looking back,
She and I ...
Did we ever have a sisterly bond?
While the sisterhood between you
and Lady Vertu is truly rare,
it cannot be expected among everyone.
But I can't understand
why she did this to me.
My Lady, you need not understand anything.
Even if one day you find out the truth,
it must be unbearably hideous.
My Lady, you are kind to Lady An.
But not everyone reciprocates your favors.
I'm aware
that right now,
I have no ability to fight back.
You are correct.
Good or ill, she did it for her own interests.
I was suspicious that Linrong might
have been manipulated by others.
But whether she was willing or not,
she did what she did.
Jinxi,
you always help me see clearly.
My Lady, you are sad because you cherish your bond.
But you need to remember that
even real sisters can turn against
each other in the harem.
Right.
Even husband and wife can turn against each other,
let alone the so-called sisters.
Your Majesty didn't sleep well again last night.
How about going for a nap?
You may go now.
Su Peisheng will serve me.
Yes.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Your Majesty.
How has she been?
You forbade people coming in or out her palace.
You surely know how to do your job.
I beg Your Majesty's forgiveness.
I am afraid that Your Majesty will be
worried after knowing her situation.
Is something wrong?
Hasn't it already passed the first three months?
Your Majesty is aware that
Concubine Sourire's innate qi
was sapped by her miscarriage.
Now she must be feeling upset
being confined in her palace.
I heard from Jinxi that
Her Highness has had one sleepless night after another.
Your Majesty,
can the imperial heir sleep well
while Her Highness cannot?
What you said is true.
It's too hot to sleep now.
Go on a walk with me.
Yes, I will have a sedan chair prepared.
Were Your Majesty's health affected by the heat,
I'd deserve a thousand deaths.
That's not necessary.
One death for you will suffice.
I will certainly have a place to chill if that happens.
Then allow me to hold a parasol for Your Majesty.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Does she often sleep restlessly like this?
My Lady started to feel the baby moving in recent days
so she can't sleep well.
That's why she looks especially exhausted.
How about her diet?
Does she eat the food sent to her?
My lady has been overwhelmed by sadness.
Her appetite has been decreasing
and she looks preoccupied while dining.
That‘s not wise of her.
She should make an effort for the child.
It's not that My lady doesn't want to ...
I know.
Your Majesty, it's been a while.
Better not to let the others notice us.
Take good care of your lady.
You‘ll benefit too.
Yes, Your Majesty.
I hope Your Highness will forgive me.
I didn't mean to intrude.
I’m just following His Majesty's decree
to accompany Your Highness in and out
and take care of Your Highness.
Take care of...
or keep a watch on...
They sound like the same order to me.
If Your Majesty feels tired,
please sit for a while.
The more months you're in your
pregnancy, the faster you feel fatigued.
If I was able to foresee today's misfortune,
I would rather Your Highness never
had to learn etiquette from me
and enter the palace to suffer.
We are not saints, Madam.
How could either of us see the future?
Actually, His Majesty still cares
a lot for Your Highness.
Does he?
Does he care for me...
Or for his child inside my belly？
His Majesty...
Peace to Your Highness.
She is just a concubine out of favor
and now bearing crimes.
Why do you have to bow to her？
Lady Joie is very straightforward.
Women in the palace are like the
flowers in the imperial garden.
Some fade, and others will bloom.
When some women age, the younger will enter.
Like a spring that never ends.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.